# **Lisa Vinson**

Lrv0828@gmail.com | 407-808-8607 | Orlando, Florida

Github: https://github.com/LiVinson | Portfolio: www.lisavinson.com

**LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lisavinson1/

Full-stack developer and QA Analyst with ability to learn new languages and processes quickly. Experience partnering with developers, QA analysts, customer support, and product owners in an agile environment to meet requirements and ensure quality products are released to clients.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS & KNOWLEDGE**

HTML5	JavaScript	Node.js	MySQL
CSS	jQuery	Express	Firebase
SCSS	React.js	Handlebars	Version Control (Git)
Bootstrap	Redux	MongoDB	RESTful APIs

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

April 2018

Full Stack Web Development Certification

## **University of Florida,** Gainesville, FL

May 2012

Bachelor of Arts, Sociology

#### **APPLICATIONS**

#### **Study SMART**

https://study-smart-app.herokuapp.com/

- Need help finding the time and motivation to study? Use Study SMART to set detailed learning
  goals, schedule and view study sessions in a monthly or weekly calendar and add resources
  for later review.
- Built with MongoDB and Mongoose, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Passport, and React-Bootstrap components.

#### **New York Times Scrubber**

https://nyt-scrubber-app.herokuapp.com

- Full stack application that allows user to query the New York Times API for articles on a particular topic, view a list of results, and save articles for later review.
- Front end rendered using React.js and Bootstrap with back-end built using MongoDB and Mongoose, Express, and Node.js,

#### **NBA Friend Finder**

https://nba-friend-finder-app.herokuapp.com

- Which NBA superstar are you most like? Users answer 10 personality questions to find out their basketball doppelganger and get a match score.
- Utilizes Bootstrap, JavaScript and jQuery to display webpage, AJAX requests to Giphy API, and Express to handle routing.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **University of Pennsylvania Coding Bootcamp, Remote**

**August 2018 - Present** 

Teaching Assistant

- Introduce core software development concepts and technologies to students, with a focus on JavaScript and MERN stack.
- Host office hours to teach additional topics such as agile methodology and provide one-onone tutoring to reinforce JavaScript concepts.

## **CentralSquare Technologies,** Lake Mary, FL

May 2018 - Present

QA Analyst I

- Author and execute test cases to ensure requirements are met, ensure adequate protection again SQL injection and cross-site scripting attacks, and identify and verify bugs during each sprint and regression period.
- Serve as scrum master, facilitating sprint planning, decomp, retro and daily stand up meetings while working with product owners to identify and remove impediments.

## PeopleScout, Inc., Charlotte, NC

**February 2014 - August 2017** 

Client Delivery Manager

*April 2017 – August 2017* 

- Managed implementation of multiple recruiting projects for an international financial services firm, leading requirements meetings with the client to determine business needs, identify project scope, and document new processes.
- Compiled weekly reports from multiple systems in Microsoft Excel to provide streamlined analysis of the recruitment status of 1,400 applicants, reducing resource needs by 50%.
- Identified and document root cause of errors for internal and client leadership, providing recommendations reducing average client escalations by 80% in 3 months.

Sr. Operations Specialist / Team Lead

February 2014 – April 2017

- Designed training curriculum for core processes, facilitating in person and virtual new hire and ongoing process training sessions for up to 30 employees in four geographic locations.
- Conducted monthly quality assessments of client's hiring process to ensure compliance with company guidelines and federal law and to provide documented, quantitative feedback to team.
- 2016 Employee of the Year awarded by senior leadership.

#### **Duke Energy, Charlotte, NC**

**April 2013 - January 2014** 

IT Security Administrator

- Created more than 3000 security access cards for Duke Energy employees and contractors in six states as part of Duke Energy merger rebranding project.
- Identified, documented, and photographed circuitry of physical access control systems at all company locations throughout eastern US, entering data into SharePoint for verification against previous records.